The algorithms have done it again.
They've introduced me to yet another
health creator. This time, Dr. Ashley
Fruise. Hopefully, I'm getting that
somewhat correct. A physician and health
educator who focuses a lot of attention
on biohacking tools. Dr. Ashley, as I
shall call her simply because I'm not
certain how to pronounce her last name
and I don't want to be continuously
rude, discusses why the peptide retatuit
is such a powerful treatment for obesity
and general health. So, we'll do what we
always do on the centrifuge. We'll go
claim by claim and apply studies to the
claims, spinning out what's correct from
what's incorrect based on the evidence.
Here's the main claims. Retatride
reduces insulin resistance and increases
metabolism as a person loses weight.
GLP-1 peptides work through reducing
hunger, but has consequences of
constipation and nausea. Tier Zepatide
is better because it dampens nausea and
leads to more weight loss. And finally,
the big one, retride is even better
because it has specialized effects.
Let's spin it.
>> So, first, just for clarity sake, you
need to know the difference between the
GLP injectables and why reat has become
the king of GLPS. The long and short of
it is that we now have good, better,
best versions of a weight loss peptide
blend that not only blunts your appetite
and decreases inflammation and insulin
resistance, but now increases your
metabolism. It's a trifecta. And the
so-called best version is reatride. But
why? Well, have you ever been told that
the more weight you lose, the lower your
metabolism will be? Well, not with
reatride. It effectively boosts your
metabolic rate while you lose fat in a
caloric deficit.
>> Right from the top, the first claim by
Dr. Ashley is that retatuitride improves
insulin resistance, the underlying
condition that causes type 2 diabetes,
and it boosts metabolism. So the first
part, improvements in insulin
resistance. Dr. Ashley is absolutely
right. One clinical study was designed
to look at exactly that. In said study
using many different dosing strategies
of retatuitride the researchers measured
a long-term marker of blood sugar called
HBA1C or glycated hemoglobin which is a
detection of a blood cell protein being
studied with sugar molecules. The higher
it is the worse after a point because it
indicates long-term elevated blood sugar
meaning that you are highly likely to be
insulin resistant. In this study, they
recruited people with severe insulin
resistance. And we can see that here
that all retitutride doses reduced this
HBA1C marker shown on the left side as
all of the lines except the control
group the placebo declined. This was
especially effective at higher doses. So
4 milligrams and upward. On the right we
see the number of people relatively
speaking that achieved a normalized
HBA1C at higher doses. 80% of people
achieved huge improvements. So the point
here being that Dr. Ashley is absolutely
right. Retutrite is highly effective
against insulin resistance. Now as for
the metabolic angle, the certainty
decreases somewhat. As far as I could
find, there are no human studies that
measure metabolism when on retride. The
claim that this peptide raises
metabolism is mentioned by the
researchers but is not proven in humans.
The reason they claim it is because of
the initial preclinical study in animals
showing that to be the case. They show
that in these data the red is the
rettoide peptide and the green is a
group not given the peptide but matched
to consume the same amount of uh as the
peptide group. So same amount of
calories and we're measuring metabolism.
So the output of energy, notice how the
peptide group did not experience a
reduction in metabolism. And yet if we
look here, there's not just equal weight
loss, but greater weight loss than the
calorierest restricted only group. So
this speaks exactly to Dr. Ashley's
point and what the researchers are
pointing out, a boosting of metabolism
even when consuming far fewer calories.
The main point here is that it is likely
that retro tried boost metabolism even
when the body is chronically exposed to
calorierestricted diet, but the evidence
is not shown in humans yet. So the
certainty is lower than that for the
insulin resistance data.
>> Here's how it works. It's a peptide
blend of GLP, GIP, and glucagon receptor
agonism. In a nutshell, GLP1 drugs hit
GLP-1 receptors all over your body
heavily in the brain and the gut. This
dumbs down your appetite and slows down
your digestion. Semaglutide is pure
GLP-1 receptor agonism, a peptide
designed to put the brakes on hunger
while constipating you and making you
nauseated. This next claim is that GLP-1
peptides work through reducing hunger
but has consequences of constipation and
nausea. For that, there are many
scientific reviews on GLP-1 peptides,
and they confirm that GLP-1 peptides do
bind to the brain. I've covered this in
past content as well, where they
influence certain neurons, so brain
cells, to not signal that there's a
stimulation of hunger. Fun fact, one of
the genes that is increased when GLP-1
peptides bind to the receptors on the
brain cells is called CART, which stands
for, get this, cocaine and empetamine
regulated transcript. And as more CART
molecules are produced from this gene,
and these molecules bind to receptors on
the neurons, causing them to stop
feelings of hunger. It's pretty nifty,
isn't it? And it is also true as
described in this same review that GLP-1
peptides can cause nausea and
gastrointestinal discomfort. So the
short of it is yes GLP-1 peptides
typically work through reducing hunger
and yes they are prone to
gastrointestinal side effects.
>> Then came tzepide a combination of GLP-1
and GIP agonism glucose dependent
insulinotropic
polyeptide. GIP is complex, but it
essentially turns your fat from being
stubborn and inflamed into a healthy
accessible fuel. It lowers inflammation
and fat, allowing you to become more
insulin sensitive and able to mobilize
fatty acids better. So why is tzepide so
much better than semaglutide? Because
there are fewer side effects and more
weight loss with that drug. And this is
because research suggests that GIP
receptors in the brain antagonize or
dampen the nausea signals triggered by
pure GLP-1 agonism. Essentially, Tzepide
hits that stop eating button while
simultaneously pushing a don't throw up
button. Tzepide is amazing because it
has less GLP-1 in it than GIP agonism.
See, GIP is doing most of the heavy
lifting. Next, tier zepide is better
because it dampens nausea and leads to
more fat loss. Fortunately, because
these peptides have been around for a
while, especially GLP-1 receptor agnus
exclusive, we have studies comparing the
two. And again, Dr. Ashley is spot on.
We can see the evidence here with the
lower the bars going, the more weight
loss occurring, primarily fat. the
semiglutide there on the right which is
the single GLP-1 receptor agonist
peptide it's clearly effective but not
as effective as tier zepatide however in
terms of side effects this same study
would disagree with the take that
there's fewer side effects overall and
even fewer nausea episodeside
showed a slightly higher proportion of
side effects compared to the single
GLP-1 receptor agonist semiglutide this
was true at higher doses. Still, two
things to consider. So, one, this could
be spec specific to the people that are
studied here, type two diabetics. And
two, you're getting more benefit with
the same potential for side effects. And
to be clear, we're also talking about a
few percent of people having side
effects, not mass amounts. This is
further confirmed in analyses of many
studies. So the point here being that
tears is better for fat loss but at
higher doses does yield more side
effects. If using a comparable dose of a
GLP-1 receptor agonist peptide alone,
you'll likely get more results at
similar side effect risk.
>> But let's shake things up even more.
Enter reatride. The scientist who
formulated this drug deserves a prize
and he probably got one. See, we really
learned a lot with this GIP to GLP1
ratio and retatride still leans heavily
on GIP receptor agonism, but it adds a
glucagon receptor peptide to the mix.
You can think of glucagon as like a fat
vacuum. In a normal functioning human,
glucagon is a fasting hormone. It tells
your liver to release sugar when you're
hungry, basically to keep you from
passing out. But in retatride because
it's paired with GLP-1 and GIP pushing
insulin and sugar into cells, the
glucagon receptor is then tricked or
diverted into doing its secondary jobs
which are lipolysis or fat burning and
thermogenesis. Basically, it increases
your metabolic idle or your resting
energy expenditure. So the claim here is
that retatuitride includes glucagon
receptor agonism to increase fat loss
and metabolism. Again this is the kind
of research where we have to rely on
pre-clinical work in animals not humans.
But if we lean on this influential study
again Dr. Ashley points out that the
glucagon aspect of the retrotutride
peptide is the part that can enhance fat
loss. And this study did some brilliant
work where they isolated the effects of
the glucagon alone from the rest of the
peptide. And sure enough, they were able
to show that if you block the glucagon
receptor, the peptide was less
effective. Not ineffective, but less
effective. And in similar vein,
revisiting metabolism, we're seeing the
peptide given in gray, maintaining
metabolism. As we saw much earlier when
we looked at the comparison against
calorie restriction. Remember this. But
the red condition in these new data is
with the glucagon receptors blockaded.
See how the metabolism is not maintained
as readily. That's because the glucagon
effect portion of the peptide is
eliminated. It's really fascinating
research. This all strongly points and
wonderfully specifically points to Dr.
Ashley being spoton. The retatride
retatrutide
has unique metabolism and weight fat
loss effects through its glucagon
addition. Okay, before I get into some
of the side effects of peptides and pull
this all together for us, you might want
to hear about something called the
futile calcium cycle caused by these
peptides or the impact that it has on
mitochondria. I'm covering those aspects
and more in my extended version of the
video that you're watching. It's
included as a Physionic Insider along
with an accompanying article, podcast,
live sessions if you're inclined. Check
out the Physionic Insiders using the
link in the description. Some final
points to quickly add. Well, I think Dr.
Ashley
knocks it out of the park, including
some of the tricker separations between
glucagon aspect and the rest of the
retrotutride.
Later, she goes into a discussion about
some of the side effects to look out
for. I'll quickly list them. Some uh
lean mass loss, which she actually
describes as muscle loss, but we can't
actually claim that outright, as lean
mass is the most common measure, and
it's made up of more than just muscle.
That isn't even to mention that weight
loss always leads to some loss in
glycogen, so stored sugar, which is also
reflected in lean mass measures. Anyway,
is it possible that there's some muscle
loss? Definitely. The second and third
she brings up are slight increases in
heart rate and slight sensations of skin
burning for some people. I'll have her
video linked for you if you care to
learn more after all that. Where does
that leave us? Well, first GLP-1
receptor agonist solopeptides like
semiglutide are effective for fat loss,
but tier zepatide is more effective and
retatuit may be even more effective.
Side effects remain for all peptides,
though the percent of people that get
side effects is quite small. And yes,
retatuitride may be especially effective
because it does have evidence it
maintains metabolism even when in a
strong calorie deficit based on early
data, giving it a mechanistic edge over
even tierepide. But let's not end it
here. We could nerd out further in other
centrifuge episodes or if you're
inclined, other epeptides. Check them
out right here. Thanks for tuning in. I
hope to see you in the next one. Every
time I say retati, I think of like
retatu.